Guide to the Walter Lowenfels Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1920-1979; Series I; 21; (50 boxes)
  - General Correspondence, 1925-1976
    - University of Wisconsin, 1971-1974, undated (Box 33, Folder 685)
    - University Place Book Shop, 1963-1975 (Box 33, Folder 686)
      Includes letters from Walter Goldwater
    - Untermeyer, Louis, 1962, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 687)
    - "V" General, 1962-1975, undated (Box 34, Folder 688)
    - Vago, Claire, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 689)
    - Vanguard Press, 1963-1971 (Box 34, Folder 690)
    - Vas Dias, Robert, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 691)
    - Vassar College, 1967-1971 (Box 34, Folder 692)
    - Veb Buromäschinenwerk Sömmerda / Thür, 1962-1964 (Box 34, Folder 693)
    - Verlag Volk und Welt (Germany), 1956-1975 (Box 34, Folder 694)
    - Viking Press, 1963-1971 (Box 34, Folder 695)
    - Vrbovska, Anca, 1963-1975 (Box 34, Folder 696)
    - "W" General, 1953-1975, undated (Box 34, Folder 697-698)
    - Wade, John Stevens, 1964-1974, undated (Box 34, Folder 699)
    - Wantling, William, 1964-1971, undated (Box 34, Folder 700)
    - War Resisters League, 1959-1976 (Box 34, Folder 701)
    - Washington University, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 702)
    - Washington State University Press, 1969-1976 (Box 34, Folder 703)
    - Weinstein, Norman, 1967, undated (Box 34, Folder 704)
    - Weiss, Lenore, 1966-1976, undated (Box 34, Folder 705-706)
    - Weiss, Ted, 1964-1965 (Box 34, Folder 707)
    - Welburn, Ron, 1967-1968 (Box 34, Folder 708)
    - Wenning, Henry, 1962-1970, undated (Box 35, Folder 709-710)
    - Wesleyan University Press, 1968-1970 (Box 35, Folder 711)
    - Wesson, Neil, 1960 (Box 35, Folder 712)
    - White, Ralph, 1960-1961 (Box 35, Folder 713)
    - White, William, 1962-1970 (Box 35, Folder 714)
    - Wickes, George, 1962-1966 (Box 35, Folder 715)
    - Wilentz, Eli, 1963-1972 (Box 35, Folder 716)
    - Willard, Nancy, 1961-1971, undated (Box 35, Folder 717)
    - William Morrow and Company, 1963-1971 (Box 35, Folder 718)
    - Williams, Harrison A., 1963-1965 (Box 35, Folder 719)
    - Williams, Jonathan, 1948-1975, undated (Box 35, Folder 720-723)
    - Williams, Loring, 1967-1968 (Box 35, Folder 724)
    - Winston, Henry, 1971-1974, undated (Box 36, Folder 725)
    - The Worker, 1953-1967, undated (Box 36, Folder 726)
    - World Books, 1961-1962 (Box 36, Folder 727)
    - World Fellowship, Inc., 1954, 1968-1972 (Box 36, Folder 728)
    - World Law Fund, 1966-1967 (Box 36, Folder 729)
    - Wormwood Review, undated (Box 36, Folder 730)
    - Wright, Jay, 1964 (Box 36, Folder 731)
    - Wright, Sarah E., 1957-1975, undated (Box 36, Folder 732-733)
    - "Y" General, 1957-1975, undated (Box 36, Folder 734)
    - Yale, David R., 1963-1964 (Box 36, Folder 735)
    - Yale University, 1960-1976 (Box 36, Folder 736)
    - Yanniello, Louis N., 1966-1972, undated (Box 36, Folder 737)
    - Young, Al, 1967-1968 (Box 36, Folder 738)
    - "Z" General, 1955-1972 (Box 36, Folder 739)
    - Zahn, Curtis, 1962-1965, undated (Box 36, Folder 740)
    - Zimmerman, Toni, 1972, undated (Box 36, Folder 741)
    - Zukofsky, Louis, 1938-1967 (Box 36, Folder 742)
    - Empty Envelopes, 1958-1968, undated (Box 36, Folder 743)
    - Identified by first name only, circa 1950-1976, undated
      - A - B, circa 1950-1976, undated (Box 37, Folder 744-758)
      - B - C, circa 1950-1976, undated (Box 38, Folder 759-768)
      - D - G, circa 1950-1976, undated (Box 39, Folder 769-788)
      - G - J, circa 1950-1976, undated (Box 40, Folder 789-804)
      - J, circa 1950-1976, undated (Box 41, Folder 805-816)
      - J - L, circa 1950-1976, undated (Box 42, Folder 817-837)
      - M - O, circa 1950-1976, undated (Box 43, Folder 838-850)
      - P - S, circa 1950-1976, undated (Box 44, Folder 851-869)
      - T - Z, circa 1950-1976, undated (Box 45, Folder 870-878)
    - Unidentified correspondence, circa 1950-1976, undated (Box 45, Folder 879-884)
    - Unidentified correspondence, circa 1950-1976, undated (Box 46, Folder 885-888)
  - Correspondence by Subject, 1935-1975
    - Letters to editors, 1951-1975, undated (Box 47, Folder 889-890)
    - Nancy Cunard's hospitalization, 1960 (Box 47, Folder 891)
    - Helen Katz property, 1935-1937, undated (Box 47, Folder 892)
    - Leroi Jones trial, 1967-1968, undated (Box 47, Folder 893-894)
    - Lillian Lowenfels's dismissal from Philadelphia public teaching position, 1947-1955, undated (Box 47, Folder 895-897)
    - Passport application, 1959 (Box 47, Folder 898)
    - Sloop Contest to Clean Up Hudson River, 1969 (Box 47, Folder 899)
    - Steven Nelson sedition case, 1952-1953, undated (Box 48, Folder 900)
    - Smith Act trial and conviction, 1953-1955, undated
      - Lowenfels, Lillian, 1954-1955 (Box 48, Folder 901-902)
      - Lowenfels, Walter, 1953-1954 (Box 48, Folder 903)
      - Third-party letters in support of amnesty or leniency for Walter Lowenfels, 1953-1954, undated (Box 48, Folder 904)
      - Other third-party correspondence, 1954 (Box 48, Folder 905)
      - Petition in support of Walter Lowenfels by Latin American writers, artists, and professionals, 1954 (Box 48, Folder 906)
      - Amnesty card correspondence and materials, 1954, undated (Box 48, Folder 907)
      - Materials relating to the Lowenfels Campaign (for amnesty, political freedom, and peace), circa 1954-1955 (Box 48, Folder 908)
      - Elizabeth Catlett biographical note and statement on her drawing of Walter Lowenfels, 1954, undated (Box 48, Folder 909)
  - Third-Party Correspondence, 1920-1979
    This series is arranged alphabetically by correspondent. A small amount of third-party correspondence that did not warrant its own folder is filed at the end of the subseries.
    - American Dialog, 1966-1968 (Box 49, Folder 910)
    - Braymer, Nan, 1961-1965, undated (Box 49, Folder 911)
    - Lowenfels, Albert, 1960, undated (Box 49, Folder 912)
    - Lowenfels, Lillian
      - A"" General, 1960-1966 (Box 49, Folder 913)
      - Apotheker, [Mother and Father], circa 1920-1932 (Box 49, Folder 914)
      - "B" General, 1950-1972, undated (Box 49, Folder 915)
      - Bantam Books, 1964-1969 (Box 49, Folder 916)
      - Bard, Phil, 1956 (Box 49, Folder 917)
      - Beacon Press, 1971 (Box 49, Folder 918)
      - Blue Heron Press, 1955 (Box 49, Folder 919)
      - Braymer, Nan, 1939, 1967, undated (Box 49, Folder 920)
      - Brooks, Edwin, 1970, undated (Box 49, Folder 921)
      - "C" General, 1955-1971, undated (Box 49, Folder 922)
      - Cunard, Nancy, 1959-1966, undated (Box 49, Folder 923)
      - Curtis Brown Ltd, 1969 (Box 49, Folder 924)
      - "D" General, 1969-1974, undated (Box 49, Folder 925)
      - Davis, George, 1931-1935, undated (Box 49, Folder 926)
      - Dodd, Mead & Co., 1971 (Box 49, Folder 927)
      - Doubleday, 1970-1972 (Box 49, Folder 928)
      - "E" General, 1957-1964, undated (Box 49, Folder 929)
      - Farrar, Straus & Girroux, 1971-1972 (Box 49, Folder 930)
      - "Friends", 1956-1967, undated (Box 49, Folder 931)
      - Fulton, Len, 1974 (Box 49, Folder 932)
      - "G" General, 1967-1971 (Box 49, Folder 933)
      - Gross, Ronald, 1970-1972 (Box 49, Folder 934)
      - "H" General, 1968, undated (Box 49, Folder 935)
      - Harper & Row, 1969 (Box 49, Folder 936)
      - Hays, Lee, undated (Box 49, Folder 937)
      - Herder & Herder, 1971 (Box 49, Folder 938)
      - Hill & Wang, 1963-1971 (Box 49, Folder 939)
      - Holt, Rinehart & Winston, 1969-1971 (Box 49, Folder 940)
      - Horizon Press, 1964-1971 (Box 49, Folder 941)
      - Hughes, Langston, 1959-1961 (Box 49, Folder 942)
      - Hugot, Shirley, 1971, undated (Box 49, Folder 943)
      - International Publishers, 1968-1971 (Box 49, Folder 944)
      - "J" General, undated (Box 49, Folder 945)
      - "K" General, 1954-1968 (Box 49, Folder 946)
      - Kane, Michal, undated (Box 49, Folder 947)
      - "L" General, 1954-1974, undated (Box 49, Folder 948)
      - Larssen, R. E. F., 1958-1968 (Box 49, Folder 949)
      - Lawson, John Howard, 1954-1967 (Box 49, Folder 950)
      - Lepeltier, M. Th., undated (Box 49, Folder 951)
      - Lowenfels, Albert, 1955, undated (Box 49, Folder 952)
      - "N" General, undated (Box 49, Folder 953)
      - "P" General, 1962 (Box 49, Folder 954)
      - Penguin, 1971 (Box 49, Folder 955)
      - Random House, 1969-1974 (Box 49, Folder 956)
      - Rapp, George, 1967-1968 (Box 49, Folder 957)
      - Recht, Jean Jacques, 1960-1962 (Box 49, Folder 958)
      - Riccio, Ottone, 1967-1970, undated (Box 49, Folder 959)
      - "S" General, 1956-1977, undated (Box 50, Folder 960)
      - Schwartz, Angela Lowenfels, 1957-1960 (Box 50, Folder 961)
      - Seeger, Pete, 1968, undated (Box 50, Folder 962)
      - Seven Seas, 1960 (Box 50, Folder 963)
      - "T" General, 1954 (Box 50, Folder 964)
      - United States District Court, 1954-1957 (Box 50, Folder 965)
      - University of Massacusetts, 1971-1975, undated (Box 50, Folder 966)
      - White, Ralph, 1960-1961 (Box 50, Folder 967)
      - First names, 1951-1974, undated (Box 50, Folder 968)
      - Unidentified, undated (Box 50, Folder 969)
    - Perpelitt, Manna Lowenfels
      - Random House, 1977-1978 (Box 50, Folder 970)
      - Stonehill Publishing Co., 1976-1977 (Box 50, Folder 971)
      - Incoming correspondence, A-Z, 1976-1979, undated (Box 50, Folder 972-975)
      - Outgoing correspondence, A-Z, 1976-1977, undated (Box 50, Folder 976)
    - Roving Eye Press, 1959-1964, undated (Box 50, Folder 977)
    - Schwartz, Angela Lowenfels, 1955-1956, undated (Box 50, Folder 978)
    - Whittier Press, 1953-1959, undated (Box 50, Folder 979-980)
    - Other third party correspondence, 1932-1976, undated (Box 50, Folder 981)
- Writings, 1926-1976; Series II; 52; (92 boxes)
  Writings are arranged alphabetically by title. Boxes of unsorted poems, anthology materials, and autobiographical materials are filed at the end of the series.
  The series contains the poetry, prose, and dramatic writings of Walter Lowenfels and drafts of works compiled and edited by Lowenfels for poetry anthologies and editions of Walt Whitman's writings. Writings are typescsript drafts with typescript and holograph corrections and notes. Among the writings are printed materials including marketing materials, newspaper clippings, and reviews, a small amount of correspondence, proofs and other related materials. Of note are Lowenfels's editions of the works of Walt Whitman, including The Tenderest Lover: The Erotic Poetry of Walt Whitman and Walt Whitman's Civil War. Both books are thematic explorations of published and unpublished writings by Whitman with commentary by Lowenfels. Lowenfels also wrote an extensive autobiography, entitled My Many Lives, the second half of which was published in The Portable Walter. To My Imaginary Daughter, published in 1954, is a small book of letters, memoirs, poems, and anecdotes that is in part autobiographical and documents Lowenfels's relationships with his own daughters. Among the many anthologies Lowenfels compiled and published in his later years, Where Is Vietnam? received the greatest attention, as it was a collection of poems protesting the war. A massive work, Autobiography of an Empire was unpublished in his lifetime. Lowenfels compiled and intended by Lowenfels to be a documentary history of the United States. Also included in this series are drafts of the anonymously published USA With Music, The Life of Fraenkel's Death, Some Deaths, Steel 1937, Sonnets of Love and Liberty and other essays and poems.
  Lowenfels frequently clipped or taped typescript fragments onto pages as corrections. Where possible, paperclips and tape have been left intact to protect the integrity of these corrections. A substantial amount of notes, drafts, and duplicates remain unidentified and unsorted. Within these unidentified files, fragments of multiple works are frequently filed together with no apparerent order.
  - "Aldington, Richard," typescript, undated (Box 51, Folder 982)
  - Alive: Letters 1934-1975, typescript, corrected (electrostatic copy), circa 1975 (Box 51, Folder 983-988)
  - "American Voices," typescript drafts, corrected, printed material, and proofs, circa 1953 (Box 52, Folder 989-994)
  - Americans For Peace, typescript, corrected, and printed material, undated (Box 52, Folder 995-996)
  - "Angela," typescript and photocopy, with corrections, undated (Box 52, Folder 997)
  - "Anonymous Books," typescript, circa 1932 (Box 52, Folder 998)
  - "Answering My Daughters (on how to read the newspapers)," clippings from Daily Worker, 1958 September 14 (Box 52, Folder 999)
  - "Aphorisms," typescript, corrected, undated (Box 52, Folder 1000)
  - "Appendix: Some Daily Worker Stories, 1946-1953," typescript, undated (Box 52, Folder 1001)
  - "Apollinaire," typescript, corrected, with notes; typescript, photocopy; printed material, undated (Box 52, Folder 1002-1003)
  - "An Artist Looks at the New Europe," newspaper clipping from Daily Worker, 1948 January 18
  - Autobiography of an Empire, 1976, undated
    - Typescript, photocopies of Introductions by Angela Davis and Maxwell Geismar, Forward by Manna Lowenfels, and Chapters I-IV, corrected., circa 1976, undated (Box 53, Folder 1004-1008)
    - "And Ain't I a Woman?" typescript and photocopy, corrected, undated (Box 53, Folder 1009-1013)
    - "The American Nightmare," typescript and photocopy, corrected, undated (Box 54, Folder 1014-1019)
    - "Which Side Are You On?" typescript and photocopy, corrected, undated (Box 54, Folder 1020-1023)
    - "Which Side Are You On?" typescript and photocopy, corrected, undated (Box 55, Folder 1024-1025)
    - "Sinning Against the Light," typescript and photocopy, corrected, undated (Box 55, Folder 1026-1027)
    - "Against the Claw," typescript drafts, corrected, undated (Box 55, Folder 1028)
    - "Lovers," typescript and typescript photocopy drafts, corrected, 1976, undated (Box 55, Folder 1029-1030)
    - "Lovers," typescript and typescript photocopy drafts, corrected, 1976, undated (Box 56, Folder 1031-1034)
    - "Sinning Against the Light," typescript, corrected, undated (Box 56, Folder 1035)
    - Various typescript drafts, corrected, with notes, undated (Box 56, Folder 1036-1038)
    - Various typescript drafts, corrected, with notes, undated (Box 57, Folder 1039-1043)
    - Various typescript drafts, corrected, with notes, undated (Box 58, Folder 1044-1049)
    - Various typescript and typescript photocopy drafts, corrected, with notes, undated (Box 59, Folder 1050-1054)
    - Source material, undated (Box 60, Folder 1055-1061)
    - Correspondence, 1963-1976 (Box 60, Folder 1062-1066)
    - Printed material, undated (Box 60, Folder 1067)
    - Empty folders, undated (Box 60, Folder 1068)
  - "Autobiography of My Poems," typescript and carbon drafts, corrected, undated (Box 61, Folder 1069-1076)
  - "The Ballad for Un-American Blues," with Lee Hays and Waldemar Hille, 1947
  - "Be Polite to the Grass: Letters to My Grandchildren," holograph, typescript and typescript photocopy drafts, corrected, undated (Box 61, Folder 1077-1081)
  - "Billionaires with Bombs," Daily Worker, 1946 August 25
  - "Black Renaissance," remarks at The National Book Awards, 1968 March 5 (Box 61, Folder 1082)
  - "Book II," typescript and photocopy, circa 1930, 1965 (Box 62, Folder 1083-1085)
  - "Christmas Prayer," printed version, undated (Box 62, Folder 1086)
  - "Christmas Spirit," newspaper clipping, circa 1938 (Box 62, Folder 1087)
  - "Communism," typescript, corrected, undated (Box 62, Folder 1088)
  - "Communist Party: Tape with Francois," typescript, corrected, undated (Box 62, Folder 1089)
  - "Constitution Day, 1951," Daily Worker, 1951 September 15
  - "Conversations with Len Chandler," typescript drafts, 1965 (Box 62, Folder 1090)
  - "Credo," Nuestro Tiempo, 1954 October (Box 62, Folder 1091)
  - "Credo of a Poet on Trial," printed material, 1954 April (Box 62, Folder 1092)
  - "Cullud: A Found Concrete Poem," copy, 1968 (Box 62, Folder 1093)
  - "The Daily Worker Drive," newspaper clipping, undated (Box 62, Folder 1094)
  - Draft Resolution on Cultural Work, typescript and holograph drafts and correspondence, 1971, undated (Box 62, Folder 1095)
  - "Dylan Thomas (1914-1953)" typescript, corrected, undated (Box 62, Folder 1096-1097)
  - "Earth Shall Smile," lyrics by Walter Lowenfels, music by Waldemar Hille., undated (Box 63, Folder 1098)
  - "Elegy in the Manner of a Requiem for D. H. Lawrence," photocopy and printed material, undated (Box 63, Folder 1099-1100)
  - "Eliot," typescript, corrected, undated (Box 63, Folder 1101-1102)
  - "Episodes and Epistles," reviews, 1926 (Box 63, Folder 1103)
  - "Epitaphs," published and unpublished poems, typescript and photocopy, with poems from Found Poems and Love Letters, undated (Box 63, Folder 1104-1105)
  - "Epithalium," broadside (Series II), undated
  - "The Eternal Meanings," American Dialog, 1969 (Box 63, Folder 1106)
  - Europe, holograph and typescript notes and newspaper clippings, 1961 (Box 63, Folder 1107)
  - Every Poem Is a Love Poem, typescript and photocopy, undated (Box 63, Folder 1108)
  - "The Execution," typescript, corrected, undated (Box 63, Folder 1109)
  - "Fascism Vs. Art," typescript, circa 1937 (Box 63, Folder 1110)
  - "Faithful to Being Alive," typescript, undated (Box 63, Folder 1111)
  - "Finale of Seem," newspaper clippings, 1929 (Box 63, Folder 1112)
  - "For a Hemiplegic," tearsheets from Mainstream, undated (Box 63, Folder 1113)
  - "For My Daughter's 20th Birthday," typescript, undated (Box 63, Folder 1114)
  - For Neruda, For Chile, 1973-1974, undated
    - Typescript and photocopy drafts, corrected, undated (Box 64, Folder 1115-1124)
    - Galleys, circa 1974 (Box 65, Folder 1125)
    - Proofs, circa 1974 (Box 65, Folder 1126-1129)
    - Source material, undated (Box 66, Folder 1130-1134)
    - Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 66, Folder 1135-1137)
    - Permissions, 1974 (Box 66, Folder 1138)
    - Printed material, 1974-1975 (Box 66, Folder 1139)
  - "For the Freedom of Morton Sobell," with Waldemar Hille, undated
  - Found Poems, typescript, typescript carbon, and photocopy drafts, and printed material, 1972-1975, undated (Box 67, Folder 1140-1141)
  - "The Fourth of July," newspaper clipping, undated (Box 67, Folder 1142)
  - "Fragment from a Life," clipping from Daily World, 1968 October 17 (Box 67, Folder 1143)
  - "From Jail," typescript drafts, undated (Box 67, Folder 1144)
  - "From Our Blood," typescript and photocopy draft, undated (Box 67, Folder 1145)
  - From the Belly of the Shark, undated
    - Typescript drafts, corrected, undated (Box 67, Folder 1146-1150)
    - Typescript drafts, corrected, undated (Box 68, Folder 1151-1158)
    - Typescript drafts, corrected, undated (Box 69, Folder 1159-1166)
    - Source material, undated (Box 69, Folder 1167-1170)
    - Printed material, 1974 (Box 69, Folder 1171)
  - "From Time to Time," newspaper clippings, undated (Box 70, Folder 1172)
  - "A Gate for Seymour Keidan," newspaper clipping, undated (Box 70, Folder 1173)
  - "Genocide," typescript, undated (Box 70, Folder 1174)
  - "Giordano Bruno," typescript and printed material, undated (Box 70, Folder 1175)
  - "Goodby Jargon" and "Welcome Home to Cubby," reprint from The Outsider, 1961 (Box 70, Folder 1176)
  - "Have We Said Enough About Spring," typescript, corrected, undated (Box 70, Folder 1177)
  - "The Hawk," reprint, undated (Box 70, Folder 1178)
  - "The Heiress Never Met the Miner," from The New Yorker, 1948
  - "Hello, Richard," newspaper clipping, 1969 (Box 70, Folder 1179)
  - "Hemingway," typescript, corrected, with printed material, 1964, undated (Box 70, Folder 1180)
  - "The Human Flow," typescsript and photocopy drafts, corrected, with holograph notes, undated (Box 70, Folder 1181)
  - "I Sat in Court with Baudelaire," newspaper clippings, 1956-1957 (Box 70, Folder 1182)
  - "The Impossible Goal," printed material, undated (Box 70, Folder 1183)
  - In the Time of Revolution, printed material and legal agreement, unsigned, 1968 (Box 70, Folder 1184-1185)
  - "In the Beginning (Some Autobiographical Letters)," typescript, undated (Box 70, Folder 1186)
  - "Index to Mankind," newspaper clipping, 1970 (Box 70, Folder 1187)
  - "Is There Not a Cause," with Karol Fahnestock, 1960 March 23
  - "Journal," typescript, undated (Box 70, Folder 1188)
  - "Korean War Letters," printed material, undated (Box 70, Folder 1189)
  - "Labor Poets," typescript drafts, corrected, 1956 (Box 70, Folder 1190)
  - Land of Roseberries, 1965
    - Typescript and photocopy, 1965 (Box 70, Folder 1191-1194)
    - Forward by Ishmael Reed, typescript drafts, with corrections, undated (Box 70, Folder 1195)
  - The Last Echo, 1969
    - Typescript and photocopy drafts, corrected, 1969 (Box 71, Folder 1196-1202)
    - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 71, Folder 1203)
    - Permissions, 1969 (Box 71, Folder 1204)
    - Printed material, 1973 (Box 71, Folder 1205)
  - Leaves of Grass, edited by WL, notes and correspondence, 1961 (Box 71, Folder 1206-1207)
  - "Len Bryansky," typescript and photocopy, corrected, 1965 (Box 72, Folder 1208)
  - "Letter Home," holograph and typescript, 1961 (Box 72, Folder 1209)
  - "Letters to Aaron Kurtz," printed version, undated (Box 72, Folder 1210)
  - "Letter to Chile," Daily World, 1974 September 6 (Box 72, Folder 1211)
  - "Letters to the Editor," typescript carbon, corrected, undated (Box 72, Folder 1212-1213)
  - "Letter to Ed Strong," newspaper clipping, undated (Box 72, Folder 1214)
  - "A Letter for the President," typescript drafts, corrected, undated (Box 72, Folder 1215)
  - "A Letter to Steve Nelson," newspaper clipping, 1954 (Box 72, Folder 1216)
  - Letters to various editors, 1928-1974, undated (Box 72, Folder 1217)
  - "Life & Death Forms," typescript letters, 1928-1938, undated (Box 72, Folder 1218)
  - The Life of Fraenkel's Death, typescript drafts, corrected, with notes, undated (Box 72, Folder 1219-1228)
  - "Lift the Embargo," newspaper clipping, undated (Box 73, Folder 1229)
  - "Literature and Society," printed material, undated (Box 73, Folder 1230)
  - Love Letters, typecript and photocopy drafts, corrected. Also contains typescript and photocopy poems by others, undated (Box 73, Folder 1231-1233)
  - Love Letters to a Hemiplegic, typescript photocopy, undated (Box 73, Folder 1234)
  - "Love Poems," typescript and photocopy, corrected, undated (Box 73, Folder 1235-1236)
  - "Love Song of Resistance," typescript drafts, 1963 (Box 73, Folder 1237-1239)
  - "Love: Synopsis for a Novel," typescript draft with notes, undated (Box 73, Folder 1240)
  - "Mae Jackson's Book of Poems," photocopy of newspaper clipping, undated (Box 73, Folder 1241)
  - "The Marchers," newspaper clippings, undated (Box 73, Folder 1242)
  - "Masthead," newspaper clipping, undated (Box 73, Folder 1243)
  - "May Day," typescript, corrected, undated (Box 73, Folder 1244)
  - "Mental Climate," typescript, corrected, undated (Box 73, Folder 1245)
  - "The Metallurgical Process," typescript and photocopy, corrected, undated (Box 74, Folder 1246)
  - [Mexico?], typescript, 1950 (Box 74, Folder 1247)
  - Modern Love: An International Anthology of Poems, typescript photocopy, undated (Box 74, Folder 1248)
  - "The Moderns," typescript, 1966 (Box 74, Folder 1249)
  - "Muga and Other Love Letters by Walter Lowenfels: Collected Poems 1929-1969," typescript, corrected (Box 74, Folder 1250-1251)
  - [Muriel?], typescript corrected, undated (Box 74, Folder 1252)
  - My Many Lives, 1950-1968, undated
    - Typescript and photocopy, corrected, 1950-1967, undated (Box 75, Folder 1253-1264)
    - "The Eternal Close," typescript and photocopy, corrected, with notes, undated (Box 76, Folder 1265-1270)
    - "Journal," typescript, corrected, undated (Box 76, Folder 1271)